# **Egle Strockyte**UX / Product Designer

# egle.strockyte@gmail.com 1 (323) 504-1778 | egle.design

# **PROFILE**

I am a product designer who enjoys solving complex problems and advocates for data driven and strategic design process. I believe that content precedes design.

I have 8+ years of in-house and agency-side experience, working with clients such as The Economist, McKinsey & Company, City of Santa Monica and Faraday Future.

#### **SKILLS**

UX Design and Strategy
Product Design
User Research & Testing
Information Architecture
Wireframing
Content Modeling
UI Design
Creative Concept Development
Typography
HTML & CSS

# **EDUCATION**

Master of Arts, Publishing (2010) University of the Arts London, LCC

Bachelor of Arts, Journalism and Media & Culture Studies (2009) Kingston University, London

Fine Arts Diploma (2005) Siauliai Art School, Lithuania

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Senior Product Designer, Bird

2019 June-present

I currently work at electric scooter startup Bird where I focus on designing meaningful experiences for our riders.

#### UX Design Director, Edenspiekermann

2016-2019

I designed digital products and experiences for brands in automotive, technology, government, publishing and finance. In my position as a UX Design Director, I owned and guided my team's design processes, methodologies and activities from concept through to finished product. I enjoyed coaching my team through challenges as much as being a hands-on member of the team at all stages of the project.

# Digital Designer, The Economist

2015-2016

I helped to create the new digital home of The Economist.
I meaningfully participated in the publication's new website ideating, prototyping, and development process, working with a large globally distributed stakeholders team.
Besides working on economist.com redesign, I was also a principle designer on the project code named CASE.
Throughout this project, I helped to reimagine The Economist's e-commerce journey by redesigning dashboard from which a logged-in user could manage their subscriptions, bookmarks and comments.

#### Designer, Global Trade Review (GTR)

2012-2015

I planned and led GTR's digital rebrand. Designed and shipped the new responsive company's website alongside the email newsletters and confirmation emails. I played key role in liaison with numerous teams including web developers, editorial and marketing.

# Freelance Designer

2011-2012

Worked on various web and print design projects for different clients. Design work mainly included responsive website mock-ups, client reports and presentations, posters and, also, physical product design.